Finding Aid for the Delmore Schwartz Papers LSC.1005
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Books from the library of Delmore Schwartz
  - Seventeenth century background: studies in the thought of the age in relation to poetry and religion. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1953, Call number: B1131.W5 (Box 42)
  - Touch of death. Greenwich, Conn.: Fawcett Publications, 1963, Call number: PS3573.I4483 T68 1963 (Box 41)
  - Little treasury of modern poetry, English & American. New York: Scribner, 1952, Call number: PR1225.W67l 1952 (Box 25)
  - Little treasury of modern poetry, English & American edited with an introduction by Oscar Williams. New York: C. Scribner's Sons, 1946, Call number: PR1225.W67l (Box 67)
  - New pocket anthology of American verse, from colonial days to the present. [New York]: Pocket Books, 1955, Call number: PS586.W53 1955 (Box 70)
  - Shake this town. New York: Paperback Library, 1964, Call number: PS3545.I5347 S52 1964 (Box 38)
  - Passage of hawks by Wirt Williams. New York: Dell, 1964, Call number: PS3573.I45622 P37 1964 (Box 42)
  - Reader's guide to T.S. Eliot: a poem-by-poem analysis. New York: Noonday Press, 1957, Call number: PS3509.L43 Z898 1957 (Box 30)
  - Gates of hell. New York: Dell, 1965, Call number: PS3545.W6769ga 1965 (Box 20)
  - Eternal fire. New York: Dell Pub. Co., 1964, Call number: PS3573.I4565 E8 1964 (Box 42)
  - Reach to the stars. New York: Dell, 1965, Call number: PS3573.I4565 1965 (Box 47)
  - Saints and strangers. New York: Ballantine Books, 1965, Call number: F68.W75 1965 (Box 20)
  - Eight essays. Garden City, N. Y.: Doubleday, 1954, Call number: PS3545.W692e (Box 20)
  - Wound and the bow: seven studies in literature. New York: Oxford University Press, 1965, Call number: PN511.W632 1965 (Box 39)
  - Georgie Winthrop. New York: Dell, 1964, Call number: PS3573.I475 G4x 1964 (Box 37)
  - Warm country with an introduction by E.M. Forester. New York: Scribner, 1960, Call number: PS3573.I5 W3 1960 (Box 39)
  - Jet set. New York, N.Y.: Dell, 1964, Call number: PS3573.O38 J48 1964b (Box 27)
  - Penguin book of French verse: with plain prose translations of each poem; introduced and edited by Brian Woledge. Harmondsworth; Baltimore: Penguin Books, 1958, Call number: PQ1165.P45 v.3-4 (Box 7)
  - Magic of their singing. New York: Macfadden, 1962, Call number: PS3573.O49 M3 1962 (Box 38)
  - Late risers: their masquerade; (formerly published as Everything happens at night). New York: New American Library, 1963, Call number: PS3573.O497 L38 1963 (Box 41)
  - Come on out, daddy. New York: MacFadden-Bartell, 1964, Call number: PS3573.O49 C66 1964 (Box 46)
  - Classic art; an introduction to the Italian Renaissance With 200 illustrations. London: Phaidon Press; Greenwich, Connecticut: dist. by New York Graphic Society Publishers, 1961, Call number: N6915.W82kE 1961 (Box 24)
  - Principles of art history: the problem of the development of style in later art translated by M.D. Hottinger. New York: Dover, 1932, Call number: N5300.W82 1932 (Box 31)
  - Orlando: a biography. [New York]: New American Library, 1960, Call number: PR6045.W883o 1960 (Box 20)
  - Second Common reader. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Co., 1932, Call number: PN511.W72 1932a (Box 20)
  - Common reader: first series. New York: Harcourt, Brace & World, 1953, Call number: PR99.W77 1953 (Box 41)
  - Mrs. Dalloway introduction by Virginia Woolf. New York: Modern Library, 1928, Call number: PR6045.O72M5 1928 (Box 58)
  - My name is Morgan. New York: Pocket Books, 1964, Call number: PS3545.W879m 1964 (Box 27)
  - Journals of Dorothy Wordsworth edited by William Knight. London: Macmillan and Co., 1924, Call number: PR5849.A8 1924 (Box 9)
  - Lyrical ballads, with a few other poems. Garden City, N. Y.: Doubleday, 1961, Call number: PR5869.L9 1961 (Box 20)
  - Heine in England with an introduction by William Clyde De Vane. Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press, 1943, Call number: PT2339.E5 W8 (Box 24)
  - Etruscan princess, and other poems. Denver: A. Swallow, 1964, Call number: PS3573.W927e (Box 15)
  - Collected poems of Sir Thomas Wyatt edited with an introduction by Kenneth Muir. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1963, Call number: PR2400.A5 M8 1963 (Box 20)
  - Collected poems of W.B. Yeats. Definitive ed., with the author's final revisions. New York: Macmillan, 1956, Call number: PR5900.A3 1956 (Box 24)
    Copy 1 in box 24, copy 2 in box 23.
  - Collected plays of W.B. Yeats. New York: Macmillan, 1953, Call number: PR5900.A4 1953 (Box 25)
  - Collected poems of W. B. Yeats. New York: The Macmillan company, 1933, Call number: PR5900.F33 1933 (Box 25)
  - Autobiography of William Butler Yeats, consisting of reveries over childhood and youth, The trembling of the veil, and Dramatis personae. Garden City, N. Y.: Doubleday, 1958, Call number: PR5906.A5 1958 (Box 31)
  - Celtic twilight: and a selection of early poems introduction by Walter Starkie. New York: New American Library, 1962, Call number: PR5904.C4 1962 (Box 67)
  - Hadrian's memoirs [translated from the French by Grace Frick, in collaboration with the author]. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, 1957, Call number: PQ2649.O8 M43 1957 (Box 67)
  - Literary opinion in America: essays illustrating the status, methods, and problems of criticism in the United States in the twentieth century. New York: Harper & Row, 1962, Call number: PN771.Z2 1962 v.1-2 (Box 39)
  - King and the corpse: tales of the soul's conquest of evil edited by Joseph Campbell. New York: Meridian Books, Inc., 1960, Call number: GR40 .Z5 1960 (Box 40)
  - Therese Raquin translated and with an introduction by Willard R. Trask. New York: Bantam Books, 1960, Call number: PQ2521.T3 E5 1960 (Box 40)
  - Germinal translated and with an introduction by L.W. Tancock. Baltimore, Maryland: Penguin, 1954, Call number: PQ2504.A31 T3 1954 (Box 42)
- Manuscript Material
  - Holograph notes by Delmore Schwartz. n.p., 11 leaves. (Box 4)
    Also, Letter to Delmore Schwartz from his student, Donna Swain. N.p. July 17, 1954 (1 leaf. Typescript signed).
  - Letters to Maurice Zolotow. Cambridge, Massachusetts and Brooklyn, New York., 3 items (4 leaves) Holograph. (Box 4)
  - Schwartz, Gertrude (Buckman) [first wife of Delmore Schwartz] Letter to Dear Jeanne. Rome., 2 leaves. Typescript, signed. (Box 4)
  - Letter from Barbara Guest to Delmore Schwartz. n.p., 1 leaf. Holograph. (Box 11)
  - Letter from Carolyn Kizer to Delmore Schwartz. Seattle., 1 leaf and envelope. Holograph. (Box 11)
  - How to read a poem by Mr. Delmore Schwartz. n.p., 1 leaf. Typescript (carbon). (Box 4)
  - Notebooks., 9 items, holograph. (Box 4)
    Photocopies of the Notebooks, 1965-1966, in Box 11.
- Miscellaneous Serials
  - Partisan Review, vol.10 no.1-5., January-October 1943 (Box 60)
  - Partisan Review, vol.9 no.1-6., 1942 (Box 60)
  - Partisan Review, vol.12 no.1-4., 1945 (Box 60)
  - Partisan Review, vol.13 no.1-5., 1946 (Box 60)
  - Partisan Review, vol.16 no.1-6., January-June 1949 (Box 61)
  - Partisan Review, vol.15 no.7-12., July-December 1948 (Box 61)
  - Partisan Review, vol.15 no.1-6., January-June 1948 (Box 61)
  - Partisan Review, vol.14 no.1-5., January-October 1947 (Box 61)
  - Partisan Review, vol.16 no.7-12., July-December 1949 (Box 62)
  - Partisan Review, vol.18 no.1-6., 1951 (Box 62)
  - Partisan Review, vol.19 no.1-6., January-December 1952 (Box 62)
  - Partisan Review, vol.17, no.1-8., 1950 (Box 62)
  - Partisan Review, vol.21 no.1-6., 1954 (Box 63)
  - Partisan Review, vol.20 no.1-6., 1953 (Box 63)
  - Partisan Review, vol.26 no.4, Fall 1959 (Box 64)
  - Partisan Review, vol.26 no.3, Summer 1959 (Box 64)
  - Partisan Review, vol.26 no.1, Winter 1959 (Box 64)
  - Partisan Review, vol.24 no.4., Fall 1957 (Box 64)
  - Partisan Review, vol.24 no.3., Summer 1957 (Box 64)
  - Partisan Review, vol.19 no.2., March-April 1952 (Box 64)
    Schwartz, pp.234-238.
  - Partisan Review, vol.15 no.3., March 1948 (Box 64)
    Schwartz, pp.279-287.
  - James Joyce Quarterly Partisan Review, vol.1 no.4. Tulsa: University of Tulsa., Summer 1964 (Box 64)
  - New World Writing, [no.]19. Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott Company, 1961 (Box 64)
  - New World Writing, [no.]19. Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott Company, 1961 (Box 64)
  - Poetry--Fiftieth Anniversary, (Double issue), vol.101, no.1 & 2, October-November 1962 (Box 64)
  - New World Writing. [no.20] Philadelphia & New York: J.B. Lippincott Company, 1962 (Box 64)
  - Paris Review, no.25, Winter-Spring 1961 (Box 64)
  - Between worlds, vol.1 no.1., Summer 1960 (Box 64)
  - James Joyce Review, vol.2 no.1-2., Spring-Summer 1958 (Box 64)
  - Poetry, vol.95 no.5, February 1960 (Box 64)
  - Partisan Review, vol.27 no.2, Spring 1960 (Box 64)
  - Harvard University Catalogue. Cambridge, Massachusetts: Harvard University Press., 1943-44. (Box 64)
  - THOTH--Journal of the English Graduate Group, vol.4 no.1. Syracuse: Department of English, Syracuse University., Winter 1963 (Box 64)
  - THOTH--Journal of the English Graduate Group, vol.5 no.1. Syracuse: Department of English, Syracuse University., Winter 1964 (Box 64)
  - The Dial, vol.1 no.1., Fall 1959 (Box 65)
  - Diogenes, no.10, 1955 (Box 65)
  - Daedalus: Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Cambridge, Massachusetts: The American Academy of Arts and Sciences., Fall, 1961 (Box 65)
  - American literature, vol.31 no.4., January 1960 (Box 65)
  - Daedalus. Vol.93 no.3., Summer 1964 (Box 65)
  - American literature, vol.32 no.2., May 1960 (Box 65)
  - Kenyon Review, vol.24 no.3, Summer 1962 (Box 65)
  - New School Bulletin, vol.18 no.18. New School for Social Research, New York., January 2, 1961 (Box 65)
  - Chicago review, vol.13 no.2. [Chicago: University of Chicago], 1959 (Box 65)
  - Art News, vol.56 no.4., Summer 1956 (Box 65)
  - Perspectives U.S.A. no.13., Autumn 1955 (Box 65)
    Schwartz, pp.70-88.
  - Perspektiven. Heft 13. Frankfurt am Main, S. Fischer Verlag., 1955. (Box 65)
  - Profils, no.6., January 1954 (Box 65)
  - Sewanee Review, vol.71 no.1, January-March 1963 (Box 65)
    SEE: Spears, Monroe K., ed.
  - Sewanee Review, vol.66 no.4, October-December 1958 (Box 65)
  - Sewanee Review, vol.68 no.4, October-December 1960 (Box 65)
  - Sewanee Review, vol.69 no.3, July-September 1961 (Box 65)
  - Perspectives U.S.A. no.10., Winter 1955 (Box 65)
    Schwartz, pp.126-136.